Okay, so let's talk about the learning
objectives for Lesson 4.
Now, lesson 4 is scope management.
Scope management is
basically documenting what
is included and what is
excluded on the project.
Scope management is about making sure
you're doing all the work necessary and
only the work necessary to complete the
project.
So we'll be talking about product scope
and project scope.
So you need to recognize
that the difference
between the scope and
the scope requirements.
What's the basic difference in the two?
I mean, essentially
you need to collect some
requirements before you
can scope out the project.
So we'll be talking about that.
You need to understand the basic approach
to scope management and understand the
difference between the predictive and the
agile approach.
The agile approach to scope management is
slightly different to
the predictive approach.
So what's the difference between the two?
You also need to understand how to collect
requirements.
There's different ways of collecting
So you will learn the requirements
solicitation techniques.
Plus the work breakdown structure.
That's an important topic in scope
management.
So you need to understand just the basic
concepts of the work breakdown structure,
what the WBS is, and
how you basically break
your project down into
its individual components.
Right.
The lowest level then would be the work.
package right and then you also talk about
the different artifacts so you need to
understand the different artifacts the
different documents that's created as well
as all of the tools and techniques right
for scope management